Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss Papers
1879 – 1964
NPKMC-223-161
1 linear foot
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss
The Weiss Papers is documentation by Brother Gerard Weiss of his family from 1879-1964. The collection includes correspondence, mortgage deeds, insurance policies, newspaper clippings, diaries and photographs pertaining to the Weiss family.
Collection Overview
The Weiss Papers consists of various sermons written by Edson E. Weiss, various photographs, letters of correspondence from Edson Weiss to Orin and Andrew Weiss, and newspaper articles on Marist and local historical sites.
The Weiss Papers was donated to Marist College Library in memory of Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss.
Historical Note
Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss was a long-time Spanish language professor at Marist College. He received his Bachelor of Arts Degree from Marian College (now Marist College) in 1949 and his Masters Degree from St. John’s University. From 1957-1975 Brother Gerard was Professor of Spanish at Marist College and during that period of time he founded the Department of Modern Languages. In 1973, he left the Marist Order, but continued on at Marist. Because of Brother Gerard’s dedication to the teaching of modern languages, a Modern Language Lab in the James A. Cannavino Library was dedicated in his memory. The Weiss Papers includes photographs of members of the Weiss family, sermons written by Edson E. Weiss, diaries of Jennie Henderson Weiss (the wife of Andrew J. Weiss), pictures, and various letters of correspondence and documents originating from Edson Weiss to his sons Orin (also knows as Orion) and Andrew Weiss.
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into two series: 1) Family History as catalogued by Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss, and 2) Additional Materials not identified in the inventory by Brother Weiss, 3) Appendix
- 1. Family History as catalogued by Brother Gerard Matthew Weiss (see appendix for a transcription of the Weiss inventory), 1; 0.66 linear feet 1 - 2 1 - 16
  Series contains a collection of letters, legal papers, mortgage papers, insurance policies, photographs and newspaper clippings preserved and catalogued by Brother Gerard Weiss. Materials are arranged in original order as described in Brother Weiss’s inventory that can be found in Folder 1.1.1. Please note that not all items that are listed in the catalogue appear in the collection.
  Numerically by catalogue number
  - Catalogues (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - Original catalogue created by Brother Weiss, 1 (Box 1)
    - Transcribed catalogue by Rita M. Popot (see appendix), 2 (Box 1)
  - Items catalogued as numbers 1-50 (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - 1B, December 23, 1965, letter from E.E. Weiss to Linden B. Johnson about school taxes and the plight of old people, 1 (Box 1)
    - 2, October 8, 1945, letter from the Kingston Associate Superintendent for Business Management to E.E. Weiss, 2 (Box 1)
    - 3, January 21, 1966, letter from Governor Rockefeller’s office to E.E. Weiss, 3 (Box 1)
    - 4, October 5, 1965, letter to The Kingston School District Board of Education, 4 (Box 1)
    - 5, January6, 1966, letter from The White House Assistant to the President to E.E. Weiss, 5 (Box 1)
    - 6, not dated, notes on capacitors, 6 (Box 1)
    - 9A, September 1, 1964, letter to Senator Hubert Humphrey from E.E. Weiss regarding a telecast on Channel 6, 7 (Box 1)
    - 9B, copy of letter sent to Senator Hubert Humphrey, 8 (Box 1)
    - 12, March 8, 1966, letter from Congressional Representative Joseph Y. Resnick to E.E. Weiss thanking him for his view of retired home owners, 9 (Box 1)
    - 13, January 25, 1966, letter to Mr. Resnick from E.E. Weiss responding to a four-page report asking for letters from retired home owners, 10 (Box 1)
    - 16, October 1964, letter from the Ulster County Community College to E.E. Weiss thanking him for his constructive comment in regard to a radio statement, 11 (Box 1)
    - 17, September 29, 1964, letter to Dale B. Lake from E.E. Weiss in regards to Mr. Lake’s misuse of grammar during a radio announcement, 12 (Box 1)
    - 18, December 7, 1964, letter to Mr. Beckwith from E.E. Weiss in regards to Mr. Beckwith’s comment that “Life Line is Highly Controversial”, 13 (Box 1)
    - 9, December 10, 1964, letter from Bob Beckwith to E.E. Weiss in response to letter labeled document 18, 14 (Box 1)
    - 20, November 15, 1963, letter to American Standard from E.E. Weiss asking for a replacement part for his Arcoflame burner, 15 (Box 1)
    - 21, July 8, 1965, letter to the Ruberoid Co. from E.E. Weiss requesting information pamphlets and booklets about their product, 16 (Box 1)
    - 25A, September 4, 1907, fire insurance policy for the dwelling owned by Andrew J. Weiss, 17 (Box 1)
    - 26, September 4, 1907, fire insurance policy from the German Company for Andrew J. Weiss, 18 (Box 1)
    - 27A, June 15, 1907, Dwelling House Insurance (Royal Company), 19 (Box 1)
    - 28, December 14, 1904, receipt of interest on mortgage payment paid by Andrew J. Weiss to O.A. Weiss, 20 (Box 1)
    - 29, July 11, 1907, Receipt for interest on mortgage payment paid by Andrew J. Weiss to O.A. Weiss, 21 (Box 1)
    - 30, January 3, 1903, Receipt of interest on mortgage paid by Andrew J. Weiss to J.M. Davis, 22 (Box 1)
    - 31, June 16, 1903, payment of interest for mortgage paid by Andrew J. Weiss to J.M. Davis (agent), 23 (Box 1)
    - 32, January 3, 1904, payment of interest paid by Andrew J. Weiss to J.M. Davis (agent), 24 (Box 1)
    - 33, December 29, 1906, payment of acct. of mortgage paid by Andrew J. Weiss to O.A. Weiss, 25 (Box 1)
    - 34, December 23, 1906, Payment of acct of mortgage by Andrew J. Weiss to O.A. Weiss, 26 (Box 1)
    - 35, July 3, 1901, Bill for $800 to be paid to Sophia le Marrill, 27 (Box 1)
    - 36, June 17, 1904, bill from Davis&Co. to Andrew J. Weiss in regards to fire insurance, 28 (Box 1)
    - 37, June 17, 1905, fire insurance policy to Andrew J. Weiss from Northwestern National Insurance Co., 29 (Box 1)
    - 39, August 21, 1922, fire insurance to Andrew J. Weiss from The Mercantile Insurance Company of America, 30 (Box 1)
    - 40A, May 2, 1944, letter to Edson Weiss from John von Blechen, 31 (Box 1)
    - 40B, May 2, 1944, envelope that item 40A came in, 32 (Box 1)
    - 41, July 17, 1944, letter to Edson Everette Weiss from 03780 Steve Ave Minneapolis, Minnesota, 33 (Box 1)
    - 42, September 5, 1944, letter to Edson Everette Weiss from O.A. Weiss, 34 (Box 1)
    - 43, June 14, 1902, mortgage paid to Andrew J. Weiss from Elizabeth herring, 35 (Box 1)
  - Items catalogued as numbers 51-100 (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - 65, Tuesday June 17- Wednesday June 25, letter from G.G. to Ed talking about the weather and personal news at home, 1 (Box 1)
    - 66, not dated, envelope containing oboe data and drawings, 2 (Box 1)
    - 67, August 21, 1922, letter from Theodore C. Steve Co. to Andrew J. Weiss in regards to the bill for the fire insurance policy, 3 (Box 1)
    - 69, September 4, 1928, fire insurance from Superior Insurance Company to Andrew J. Weiss, 4 (Box 1)
    - 71, August 15, 1904, bill from Minneapolis Gas Light Company to Andrew J. Weiss, 5 (Box 1)
    - 73, November 4, 1943, letter from Bob at The Elastic Stop Nuts Corp. to O.A. Weiss, 6 (Box 1)
    - 74, letter from Bob at the Elastic Stop Nuts Corp. to Orin A. Weiss as an acknowledgement of a letter O.A. Weiss sent between November 4, 1943 and November 19, 1943, 7 (Box 1)
    - 75, June 30, 1944, receipt from Georgia M. Erickson to E. Weiss, 8 (Box 1)
    - 78, July 12, 1944, court judgment where the family of A.J. Weiss (deceased) will not be responsible for the debt of A.A. Weiss., 9 (Box 1)
    - 83, not dated, sermon on Matthew 4, 13, 10 (Box 1)
    - 87A, October 22, 1964, letter to Mr. Agor from E.E. W. thanking for editorial on LBJ, 11 (Box 1)
    - 87B, October 19, 1969, envelope from letter from Mr. Agor, 12 (Box 1)
    - 89C, December 25, 1941, envelope from letter from Ruth to Andrew and Edson, 13 (Box 1)
  - Items catalogued as numbers 101-150 (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - 107, Saturday, card to Ed from Ponnil expressing sympathy for father’s death, 1 (Box 1)
    - 109, Saturday morning, letter to Orin from G.G.E thanking him for birthday remembrance, 2 (Box 1)
    - 111, not dated, sermon on 1 Corinthians 29, 15, 3 (Box 1)
    - 112, not dated, sermon on Romans 14.7-10, 4 (Box 1)
    - 113, not dated, sermon on James 1, 25 Genesis 28, 20, 22, 5 (Box 1)
    - 114, not dated, sermon on the gospel where the man sends off 3 servants, 6 (Box 1)
    - 115, not dated, sermon on Ezekiel 11, 19th, 7 (Box 1)
    - 116, not dated, sermon on Acts 3, 8, 8 (Box 1)
    - 117, not dated, sermon on the First Book of Romans, 9 (Box 1)
    - 118, not dated, sermon on John, 10 (Box 1)
    - 119, not dated, sermon on John 1 and Revelation 5, 9, 11 (Box 1)
    - 120, not dated, sermon on John 1, 12 (Box 1)
    - 121, not dated, sermon on John 10, 26, 13 (Box 1)
    - 122, not dated, sermon on Hebrews 9, 15 and John 1, 14 (Box 1)
    - 123, not dated, sermon on Isaiah 61, 3, 15 (Box 1)
    - 124, not dated, sermon on the relationship of Jacob and Laban, 16 (Box 1)
    - 125, not dated, sermon not described, 17 (Box 1)
    - 126, not dated, sermon of Galatians 4, 22, 19, 18 (Box 1)
    - 127, not dated, sermon on Luke 29, 13, 14, 19 (Box 1)
    - 128, not dated, sermon on Ezekiel, 20 (Box 1)
    - 129, not dated, sermon on Mark 2, 10, 21 (Box 1)
    - 130, not dated, sermon on Meal. 4, 2, 22 (Box 1)
    - 131, not dated, sermon PS 62, 2 and John 13, 2, 23 (Box 1)
    - 135, 1952, letter from Edson Weiss to Jim and Jane telling them about his recent move to New York, 24 (Box 1)
    - 136, January 17, 1952, letter to Edson from Marie on Masonic temple paper, 25 (Box 1)
    - 140A, February 5, 1952, letter to Sou Pewey form E. Weiss commenting on the increase in real estate taxes in NYC. 140B, February 5, 1952, letter to Mayor Impellitteri from E. Weiss discussing the increase in real estate taxes, 26 (Box 1)
    - 142, February 8, 1952, letter to I. Rvins from Edson, 27 (Box 1)
    - 144, not dated, sermon on Mark 26-29, 28 (Box 1)
    - 145, not dated, sermon on Our Redemption, Isaiah 42, 16 and Rev. 5, 9, 29 (Box 1)
    - 146, not dated, sermon on 2 Corinthians 9, 11, 30 (Box 1)
    - 147, not dated, sermon on Genesis 4, 9, 10, Isaiah 40, 1, 2 and 1 Timothy 6,12, 31 (Box 1)
    - 148, not dated, sermon on 1Corinthians3, 20, 32 (Box 1)
    - 149, not dated, sermon Col. 3, 1-4, 33 (Box 1)
    - 150, not dated, sermon on SS. 2,3,4, 34 (Box 1)
  - Items catalogued as numbers 151-200 (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - 151, not dated, sermon on Acts 11, 26, 1 (Box 1)
    - 152, not dated, sermon on Luke 4, 8 and Col. 3, 1-3, 2 (Box 1)
    - 153, not dated, sermon on Matthew 22, 11, 12, 3 (Box 1)
    - 154, not dated, sermon on 1 Cor. 6, 20, 4 (Box 1)
    - 155, not dated, sermon on Matthew 26, 29-9, 5 (Box 1)
    - 159, not dated, sermon on John 6, 6-8 and Jer. 13-23, 6 (Box 1)
    - 160, not dated, sermon on 1 Tim 1-15 and Luke 10, 42, 7 (Box 1)
    - 161, not dated, sermon on Ezekiel 2, 19, 22, 8 (Box 1)
    - 162, not dated, sermon on Exodus 32, 26 and Ezekiel 3, 17, 21, 18th and 33, and 2 Cor. 7, 10, 9 (Box 1)
    - 163, not dated, sermon, Ezekiel 2, 19-22, 10 (Box 1)
    - 164, not dated, sermon on Matthew 13, 30, 11 (Box 1)
    - 165, not dated, sermon on Meal? 4, 2, 12 (Box 1)
    - 166, not dated, sermon on Exodus 20, 8-10, 13 (Box 1)
    - 167, not dated, sermon on Isaiah 42, 16, 14 (Box 1)
    - 168, not dated, sermon Col. 1, 28 and John 1, 29, 15 (Box 1)
    - 169, not dated, sermon on Col. 1, 28, 16 (Box 1)
    - 171, not dated, letter from Bette Weiss (cousin) to Orin, 17 (Box 1)
    - 176, not dated, unidentified sermon, 18 (Box 1)
    - l 77, not dated, sermon on Malach? 3, 10, 19 (Box 1)
    - 178, not dated, sermon on Prov. 3, 56 and Acts 16, 30, 20 (Box 1)
    - 179, not dated, sermon on Romans 14, 7-10 and Numbers 14, 23, 24, 21 (Box 1)
    - 180, not dated, sermon on John 10, 16, 22 (Box 1)
    - 181, not dated, sermon on Joel 2, 18l 17, 12, 13 and Jer. 6, 16, 23 (Box 1)
    - 182, not dated, sermon on Proverbs 20, 1, 24 (Box 1)
    - 183, not dated, sermon on Ezekiel, 1, 19, 20, 25 (Box 1)
    - 184, not dated, sermon on 1 Tim 1, 14, 15, 26 (Box 1)
    - 185, not dated, sermon on Hebrews 11, 25, 27 (Box 1)
    - 186, not dated, sermon on Luke 10, 42 and john 21, 17, 28 (Box 1)
    - 187, 1909, card from Edna to Orin, 29 (Box 1)
    - 190A, July 30, 1979, card to Gladys from Lucy Aita and daughter Joan, 30 (Box 1)
    - 190B, 1979, bookmarker from Florence wishing Gladys a Happy Easter, 31 (Box 1)
    - 193, Thursday Morning, letter from Edson to G.G., 32 (Box 1)
    - 194, September 26, 1919, insurance policy to Andrew J. Weiss from Insurance Company of North America and the Fire Ass. Of Phil., 33 (Box 1)
  - Items catalogued as numbers 200-244 (Folder 6, Box 1)
    - 203, December 8, 1902, receipt from A.J. Weiss to Elizabeth J. Herring in the sum of $28 for the interest on loan of $800, 1 (Box 1)
    - 204, June 13, 1904, receipts form A.J. Weiss to J. Wassett in the sum of $24 in interest on loan, 2 (Box 1)
    - 205, December 10, 1902, receipts for fire insurance policy of 1902, 3 (Box 1)
    - 206, Filed December 11, 1888, legal document giving M.J. Robertson power of attorney over Lewy Robertson, 4 (Box 1)
    - 207, Filed November 1885, papers giving power of attorney from Matt J. Robertson to Leway Robertson, 5 (Box 1)
    - 208, June 13, 1902, warranty deed for dwelling of A.J. Weiss, 6 (Box 1)
    - 209, June 17, 1925, fire and or tornado insurance from Royal Insurance Co. to A.J. Weiss, 7 (Box 1)
    - 211, August 28, 1916, fire insurance policy from Germania Fire Insurance Co. to A.J. Weiss, 8 (Box 1)
    - 212, July 24, 1905, tornado insurance policy from The Northwestern National Insurance Co. to A.J. Weiss, 9 (Box 1)
    - 213, filed on April 20, 1908, assignment of mortgage to August Weiss and Oscar A. Weiss, 10 (Box 1)
    - 214, November 12, 1909, assignment of mortgage from Augusta Weiss to Oscar A. Weiss, 11 (Box 1)
    - 215, filed July 5, 1901, mortgage deed from August Mechin to Sophia Merrill, 12 (Box 1)
    - 216, May 24, 1902, earnest money contract of sale as receipt for purchase of house from Augusta Mechin to A.J. Weiss, 13 (Box 1)
    - 217, filed July 2, 1904, assignment of mortgage from Sophia le Manill to Augusta Weiss, 14 (Box 1)
    - 218, filed January 17, 1905, assignment of mortgage from Elizabeth Herring to Mrs. Augusta Weiss, 15 (Box 1)
    - 219, filed June 13, 1902, mortgage deed from Andrew Weiss to Elizabeth Herring, 16 (Box 1)
    - 223, July 1944, an affidavit stating that Orin and Edson could receive at Veissor estate, 17 (Box 1)
    - 226, June 25 and 26, 1969, letter from Edson to G.G. talking about the weather and politics, 18 (Box 1)
    - 231, August 21, 1944, letter from Mary to Mom, 19 (Box 1)
    - 232, not dated, sermon on Luke 16, 26, 20 (Box 1)
    - 233, not dated, sermon on Acts 11, 26 and Proverbs 18, 24, 21 (Box 1)
    - 238, March 27, 1951, letter from Edson to Gladys, 22 (Box 1)
    - 239, March 29, 1952, letter from Ed to Gladys, 23 (Box 1)
    - 240, April 1, 1952, letter from Gladys and Edison to the Folks, 24 (Box 1)
    - 243, Thursday, letter from Ed to Orin discussing Ed’s move to New York and leaving the house in Minnesota, 25 (Box 1)
    - 244, not dated, pictures of leaves, 26 (Box 1)
  - Numbered newspaper clippings (Folder 7, Box 1)
    - 47, not dated, clipping titled “Protecting the American Home” comes from A Hero of Ticonderoga by Rowland Robinson, 1 (Box 1)
    - 49, © 1948, Walt Disney Production World Rights Reserved No.1-15 of a banged up cat that tries to see in the dark, 2 (Box 1)
    - 50, © 1948, Walt Disney Production of a turtle who stopped suddenly, 3 (Box 1)
    - 51, © 1948, Walt Disney Production of a black panther that worries about gray hairs because they will really show, 4 (Box 1)
    - 52, © 1948, Walt Disney Production no. 3-2 of a monkey who thought his tail was a snake when there is a lead on the top of the tip, 5 (Box 1)
    - 53, © 1948, Walt Disney Production of one goat asking another goat is it ate any good books lately, 6 (Box 1)
    - 54, not dated, cartoon of Donald Duck holding a gold bag, sweating with the sun coming down on him, 7 (Box 1)
    - 55, not dated, illustration by Fishchette of four crows on one branch wearing hats of different nations (America, Russia, India, Latin America), 8 (Box 1)
    - 56, not fated, from the Saturday Evening Post and illustration of a hillbilly bear a Walt Disney character with music in the background, 9 (Box 1)
    - 57, © 1948, Walt Disney Production No.1-21 of an octopus tied up in knots with the caption that reads “Ever have one of those days when nothing seems to go right?”, 10 (Box 1)
    - 58, © 1948, Walt Disney Production No. 8-6 of a cat quietly coming down the stairs with the caption that reads “Boy, what a night he must’ve had! He just yelled at me to quit stomping!”, 11 (Box 1)
    - 59, © 1948, Walt Disney Production of an alligator in a sway yelling “Chloe…Chloooeee!”, 12 (Box 1)
    - 60, © 1948, Walt Disney Production No. 12-7 of two beavers talking about a third in it’s dam and the caption reads “I’ll say she’s prudish. She calls it a Darn!”, 13 (Box 1)
    - 61, © 1948, Walt Disney Production No. 5-1 of two beavers talking about recipes made up of different types of wood, 14 (Box 1)
    - 62, not dated, three illustrations of a man taking a picture of some moneys in the Saturday Evening Post by nick Ruble, 15 (Box 1)
    - 63, not dated, illustration by I. Alexander caption reads “It’s past your bed tie son, put your toys away.”, 16 (Box 1)
    - 64, © 1949, a comic book on “The Amazing story of Measurement” prepaid and distributed by the Larkin Rule Co., 17 (Box 1)
    - 93, not dated, illustration of a worker doing nothing but balancing things on his desk, 18 (Box 1)
    - 94, 1946, illustration in the N.Y. Tribune called “Paper Profits” by Webster, 19 (Box 1)
    - 106, November 22, 1923, title “Robbed of Jewels” person in question Mrs. Ray van Chief of Buffalo, N.Y., 20 (Box 1)
    - 191, not dated, picture of a cat grasping a mouse some one has written “Now tell me! Is you a mouse or is you a man”, 21 (Box 1)
    - 195, not dated, illustrations of Mickey Mouse in 1931 and the other of him in 1933, 22 (Box 1)
    - 196, © 1949, Walt Disney Production No. 2-26 of two alligators, 23 (Box 1)
    - 197, © 1949, Walt Disney Production No. 2-26 of three monkeys, 24 (Box 1)
    - 198, © 1949, Walt Disney Production of two monkeys with one picking has up and the other lifting his feet, 25 (Box 1)
    - 199, not dated, New York Times picture of Mickey in 1947 after 20 years, 26 (Box 1)
    - 200, not dated, 1927 illustration of the first Mickey Mouse silent picture, 27 (Box 1)
    - 220, not dated, picture of Mark Twain in his latter year writing bed, 28 (Box 1)
    - 224, not dated, picture of two men handcuffed together these en were kidnapped by gem bandits, 29 (Box 1)
    - 225, not dated, Walt Disney Production of greedy hillbilly wolf with musical notes floating around him, 30 (Box 1)
    - 234, © 1936, Illustration 4-13 of Beetle Bailey, 31 (Box 1)
    - 235, © 1936, Thimble Theatre staring Popeye No. 12-10 by Ralph Stern and Bill Zaboly, 32 (Box 1)
    - 237, © 1944, comic strip titled “They’ll do it Every Time” by Jimmy Halto Illustration No. 6-20, 33 (Box 1)
    - 241, not dated, picture of Mark Twain’s Hartford house, 34 (Box 1)
    - 242, not dated, picture of Mark Twain writing in his favorite place, his bed, 35 (Box 1)
  - Letters and Notes by Edson E. Weiss (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - Letters and Notes for 1950, 1 (Box 1)
    - Letters and Notes for 1951, 2 (Box 1)
    - Letters and Notes for 1952, 3 (Box 1)
  - Notes on Various Topics A-W by Orin Weiss (Folder 9, Box 1)
    - Accuracy, July 8, 1937, 1 (Box 1)
    - Aesop, July 10, 1937, 2 (Box 1)
    - Art, November 28, 1936, 3 (Box 1)
    - A.S.M.E., 1938, 4 (Box 1)
    - Atom, 1937, 5 (Box 1)
    - Bible, April 26, 1938, 6 (Box 1)
    - Books, October 11, 1936, 7 (Box 1)
    - Brisbane, May 10, 1937, 8 (Box 1)
    - Buildings, November 9, 1937, 9 (Box 1)
    - Business, August 3, 1936, 10 (Box 1)
    - Charts, not dated, 11 (Box 1)
    - Crime, January 5, 1937, 12 (Box 1)
    - Criticism, December 7, 1936, 13 (Box 1)
    - “Culored Folks”, July 10, 1937, 14 (Box 1)
    - Depressions, November 28, 1936, 15 (Box 1)
    - Description, January 27, 1936, 16 (Box 1)
    - Economics, April 1, 1935, 17 (Box 1)
    - Education, December 7, 1936, 18 (Box 1)
    - Employment, January 9, 1937, 19 (Box 1)
    - Examinations, May 27, 1938, 20 (Box 1)
    - Farmers, August 29, 1936, 21 (Box 1)
    - Fools, September 21, 1937, 22 (Box 1)
    - Freud, August 26, 1938, 23 (Box 1)
    - Ghetto, April 15, 1937, 24 (Box 1)
    - Gifts, January 27, 1936, 25 (Box 1)
    - Glass (Carter), August 29, 1936, 26 (Box 1)
    - Gold, January 5, 1937, 27 (Box 1)
    - Gorki, February 23, 1938, 28 (Box 1)
    - Government, November 20, 1936, 29 (Box 1)
    - Happiness, October 11, 1936, 30 (Box 1)
    - ypocrisy, July 10, 1937, 31 (Box 1)
    - Inventions, June 27, 1936, 32 (Box 1)
    - Jews, May 10, 1937, 33 (Box 1)
    - Joy, not dated, 34 (Box 1)
    - law, May 10, 1937, 35 (Box 1)
    - Lectured, October 13, 1936, 36 (Box 1)
    - Lending, December 1936, 37 (Box 1)
    - Life- A Study in Caution and Values, August 21, 1933, 38 (Box 1)
    - Liquor, July 10, 1937, 39 (Box 1)
    - Living, August 22, 1936, 40 (Box 1)
    - Markets, February 23, 1938, 41 (Box 1)
    - Marriage, November 28, 1936, 42 (Box 1)
    - Marx, march 28, 1938, 43 (Box 1)
    - Night Spots, July 10, 1937, 44 (Box 1)
    - Of Mother, June 6, 1936, 45 (Box 1)
    - Photography, July 30, 1935, 46 (Box 1)
    - Production, December 1936, 47 (Box 1)
    - Psychology, September 2, 1937, 48 (Box 1)
    - Reading, August 26, 1938, 49 (Box 1)
    - Salesmanship, October 11, 1936, 50 (Box 1)
    - Smith, not dated, 51 (Box 1)
    - Social Welfare, November 2, 1936, 52 (Box 1)
    - Society, October 11, 1936, 53 (Box 1)
    - Taxes, May 10, 1937, 54 (Box 1)
    - War, January 27, 1936, 55 (Box 1)
    - We-O’Learys are a Strange Crowd, September 5, 1936, 56 (Box 1)
    - Wine, 1933, 57 (Box 1)
    - Women, August 22, 1936, 58 (Box 1)
    - Writing, July 30, 1935, 59 (Box 1)
  - Diary B (Folder 11, Box 2)
    - 133, 1901, diary to Jennie Henderson from her father, 1 (Box 2)
  - Diary C (Folder 12, Box 2)
    - 134, 1902, diary to Jennie from Papa, 1 (Box 2)
  - Diary D (Folder 13, Box 2)
    - 172, 1903, diary to Mrs. A.J. Weiss from Papa, 1 (Box 2)
  - Diary E (Folder 14, Box 2)
    - 173, 1899, diary to Jennie Henderson from her brother Charles, 1 (Box 2)
  - Diary F (Folder 15, Box 2)
    - 174, June 18, 1902, wedding book with pictures of A.J. Weiss and Jennie H. Weiss and a picture of the house at 3708 Stevens Ave. with wedding invitation numbered 87A folded inside, 1 (Box 2)
  - Photographs numbered for the catalogue by Brother Weiss (Folder 16, Box 2)
    - P1, October 11, 1902, picture of A.J. Weiss at age 34 years 3 month and 12 days to Miss Henderson, 1 (Box 2)
    - P2, August 15, 1902, picture of Jennie B. Henderson at age 24 years 4 months 35 days, 2 (Box 2)
    - P3, December 1, 1899, picture of Jennie Henderson at the age of 20, 3 (Box 2)
    - P4, not dated picture of the living room in the house at 3708 Stevens Ave, 4 (Box 2)
    - P5, not dated, Jennie’s mother called the “madman”, 5 (Box 2)
    - P7, not dated, photo of Jennie naked sitting pool side, 6 (Box 2)
    - P8, not dated, photo of Albert McCall, 7 (Box 2)